<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://devre.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://devre.co/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-21T09:07:59+09:00</updated><id>https://devre.co/</id><title type="html">DEVREL - Agency developer relations -</title><subtitle>The Developer Relations support industry is realizing a world where developers can have a better development experience. We support all of your developer relations.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Large-scale DevRel Event Types and Objectives</title><link href="https://devre.co/event/2019/05/20/devrel-event.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Large-scale DevRel Event Types and Objectives" /><published>2019-05-20T09:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-05-20T09:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://devre.co/event/2019/05/20/devrel-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://devre.co/event/2019/05/20/devrel-event.html">&lt;p&gt;It’s possible to classify events into several types. First, there are in-house events. Famous examples are Build, de:code, and AWS Summit. Of course, the event’s scale doesn’t have to be that large. Also, it may be user-driven even though named as a company service event like well-known examples such as JAWS DAYS and Backlog World.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a different viewpoint, there are also events concerning specific technologies. For user-driven events, there are various events such as RubyKaigi, PyCon, try! Swift, and Android Bazaar and Conference. The company can still take the lead in hosting the event despite it concerning specific technologies. Well-known examples are ad:tech Tokyo, CloudNative Days, and Developers Summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/articles/event-pattern.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, we’ll explain the characteristics of each of these four patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;company-services-x-company-held-events&quot;&gt;Company Services x Company-held Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An event concerning the services of one’s company, organized and held with the company’s initiative. The speaker is an expert in a specific technology and calls out some of the users to stand on stage. Listed below are some well-known examples of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/wwdc19/&quot;&gt;WWDC&lt;/a&gt;（Apple）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://events.google.com/io/&quot;&gt;Google I/O&lt;/a&gt;（Google）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.f8.com/&quot;&gt;F8&lt;/a&gt;（Facebook）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://githubuniverse.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Universe&lt;/a&gt;（GitHub）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/ja-jp/events/decode/2019/default.aspx&quot;&gt;de:code&lt;/a&gt;（Microsoft）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.discovery2019.soracom.jp/&quot;&gt;SORACOM Conference Discovery&lt;/a&gt;（SORACOM）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/build&quot;&gt;Microsoft Build&lt;/a&gt;（Microsoft）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://aws.amazon.com/jp/summits/tokyo-2019/&quot;&gt;AWS Summit Tokyo&lt;/a&gt;（AWS）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://linedevday.linecorp.com/jp/2018/&quot;&gt;LINE DEVELOPER DAY&lt;/a&gt;（LINE）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also small events, but when it comes to opening your own company’s event, it can range to all sorts of scales (hundreds-thousands). While there are times when it’s only done by one’s own company, there are also many cases when it’s partner-centric, gathering supporting companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your event’s objective is likely to increase the presence of your company and its services. If it’s a large-scale event, it’s likely to get more exposure to the media and spread across social networks. If it’s a once in a year chance, it can gather participants throughout the country (or the world). It can be enjoyed as a kind of festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increased loyalty is also tied to the event’s refinement. While talks in regular study sessions are based on the current situation, conferences announce features that will be released in the future. By meeting or exceeding developer expectations, you can reassure them and renew their desire to keep using your services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;company-services-x-user-held-events&quot;&gt;Company Services x User-held Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An event organized by the users (community). As a community, we believe that it’s likely one of the things we should aim for. Even though it’s for your company’s services, you’re not involved with the management, so if you don’t have much heat going on, the event probably wouldn’t be successful and many wouldn’t think of holding one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jawsdays2019.jaws-ug.jp/&quot;&gt;JAWS DAYS&lt;/a&gt;（AWS）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://backlog.com/ja/backlog-world/&quot;&gt;Backlog World&lt;/a&gt;（Backlog）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://connect2019.jpstripes.com/&quot;&gt;JP_Stripes Connect&lt;/a&gt;（Stripe）&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mtddc2018.mt-tokyo.net/&quot;&gt;MTDDC Meetup TOKYO&lt;/a&gt;（Movable Type）&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it’s user-driven, its main goal is likely for fellow users to have fun and communicate with each other. At a conference, the chairperson is usually the most fired up, but also the one shouldering the heaviest burden, which can lead to burnout. It can lead to a good cycle, but can also slow you down if you don’t start looking for the next leader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specific-technology-x-company-held-events&quot;&gt;Specific Technology x Company-held Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an event held by a specific company’s initiative focusing on specific technologies. Its advantages are that you can easily control the frequency and size of the event and gather customers attracted to the technological trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://adtech-tokyo.com/ja/&quot;&gt;ad:tech Tokyo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudnativedays.jp/&quot;&gt;CloudNative Days&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://event.shoeisha.jp/devsumi&quot;&gt;Developers Summit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ledge.ai/the-ai-2018/&quot;&gt;THE AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apithedocs.org/&quot;&gt;API the Docs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the major problem is where to put your company’s presence. If you highlight it too much, it can be seen as a commercial event. This kind of event should be held with emphasis on being technically neutral. However, being too neutral may lead to your company and its products being left unknown despite the event becoming famous. Your competitors might end up being the ones getting sponsored instead, robbing you of your due.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specific-technology-x-user-held-events&quot;&gt;Specific Technology x User-held Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what is called a community sponsored developer event. Examples of this event are too many to mention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://rubykaigi.org/2019&quot;&gt;RubyKaigi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pycon.jp/2018/&quot;&gt;PyCon JP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tryswift.co/events/2019/tokyo/jp/&quot;&gt;try! Swift&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://builderscon.io/&quot;&gt;builderscon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://abc.android-group.jp/&quot;&gt;Android Bazaar and Conference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://droidkaigi.jp/&quot;&gt;DroidKaigi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://iosdc.jp/&quot;&gt;iOSDC Japan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A community event with the developer community as its base, organized with their passion. In many cases, it’s done for each programming language, but it can also be for software and frameworks such as React Conf and SeleniumConf. In that sense, many communities held by connpass and Doorkeeper can be the target for conferences and large-scale events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holding a large-scale event can be a daunting task. If it’s company-based, the person in charge can do it as part of their job. The budget is also allocated by the company, with the event being carried out within that range. For user-held events, they can’t be held if there’s no heat going on with your products or services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MOONGIFT attends to training involving event hosting and developer communities. We respond to various needs, such as wanting to raise a developer community which can host large-scale events, and wanting to properly conduct company-held events. First of all, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;feel free to contact us.&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>moongift</name></author><summary type="html">It’s possible to classify events into several types. First, there are in-house events. Famous examples are Build, de:code, and AWS Summit. Of course, the event’s scale doesn’t have to be that large. Also, it may be user-driven even though named as a company service event like well-known examples such as JAWS DAYS and Backlog World.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Difference between Public Relations and DevRel</title><link href="https://devre.co/public%20relations/pr/2019/05/15/pr-devrel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Difference between Public Relations and DevRel" /><published>2019-05-15T09:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-05-15T09:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://devre.co/public%20relations/pr/2019/05/15/pr-devrel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://devre.co/public%20relations/pr/2019/05/15/pr-devrel.html">&lt;p&gt;DevRel is an abbreviation of Developer Relations, which can be described as the developer version of Public Relations. So what exactly is Public Relations? In Japan, it means publicity. Many usually understand publicity as work where one broadcasts oneself. However, Public Relations, in addition to publicity, also has the role of hearing out the public. In a sense, publicity alone omits that role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public Relations can be thought of as a corporation and also a member of society, playing the role of satisfying stakeholders from all directions. Suppose that a project for building a mall in a regional city was launched. It will undoubtedly arouse opposition from the locals. The roads would probably become congested. Things would likely get noisier in that once quiet place, and there’s also the possibility of logging down the forests, making it a life-and-death problem for the small shopping district. It’s the role of Public Relations to give explanations to those who would become stockholders, take in their feedback, and find common ground. For example, they could design a parking route to prevent traffic jams, arrange for security guards, or help maintain the park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doing these activities is the role of Public Relations. Developer Relations, or DevRel, is its developer version. DevRel regards developers as stakeholders, and utilizes their feedback and shared information in service development, shouldering both the role of publicity and consulting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those in charge of Public Relations do not force their company’s opinions but instead take on the role of properly taking in the opinions of the general public and conveying them to the management. When being affiliated with a company, there’s a tendency of thinking the company’s rules to be common sense. To avoid that, it’s important to establish yourself as the company’s conscience. Even in DevRel, the people involved (especially the Evangelist Advocate) must strive to be technically neutral, rather than being fixated on their company’s products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-trust&quot;&gt;Building Trust&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many outside developers probably come to the Evangelist Advocate for consultations. During such times, many usually feel that they can manufacture their own products but doing so isn’t the best option. During such cases, it’s possible to get more users by promoting your in-house manufactured products. However, as it’s not the best option, there may be a lot of questions, or tricky techniques required, which may result in loss of trust from the developer. If you’re recommending products from other companies, you won’t get to increase your product’s users but can build developer trust. Doing so, you’re probably going to get some questions again the next time you encounter a similar situation. In DevRel, one should focus on building mid-long term trust rather than short term user increase/decrease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a tendency of moving toward near-sighted goals due to marketing policies, but even if the number of users increases in the short run, the limits are immediately visible. It’s said that the top priority of &lt;a href=&quot;https://logmi.jp/business/articles/32512&quot;&gt;AirBnB is to satisfy the first 100 users&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the same for DevRel. First of all, one must solve the user’s problems and dissatisfaction, and build trust between them. Those satisfied users will then bring along other users. Creating that cycle will likely lead to your service’s success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Public Relations and DevRel have different target groups, their goal remains the same. One must place importance not only on publicity, but also hear out the target group, take in their feedback, and achieve one’s company’s goals. Please don’t forget to take in these viewpoints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MOONGIFT accepts DevRel support. We undertake work such as acting as an agent for the Evangelist Advocate, blog writing, and document management in order to spread your services. If you have any issues regarding DevRel, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;please contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>moongift</name></author><summary type="html">DevRel is an abbreviation of Developer Relations, which can be described as the developer version of Public Relations. So what exactly is Public Relations? In Japan, it means publicity. Many usually understand publicity as work where one broadcasts oneself. However, Public Relations, in addition to publicity, also has the role of hearing out the public. In a sense, publicity alone omits that role.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The three values that classify DevRel’s initiatives</title><link href="https://devre.co/devrel/2019/05/14/devrel-value.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The three values that classify DevRel's initiatives" /><published>2019-05-14T09:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-05-14T09:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://devre.co/devrel/2019/05/14/devrel-value</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://devre.co/devrel/2019/05/14/devrel-value.html">&lt;p&gt;If DevRel is looked at as a “marketing method to spread products and services targeting developers,” one might think that it cannot be used if such services are not being made. However, DevRel is something that forms good and continuous relations with developers, so it is an initiative that has a large range and can be used more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will now look at DevRel from three different perspectives and consider those values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;direct-revenue-type&quot;&gt;Direct revenue type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having in-house manufactured products and services be used leads to the profit of the company. For example, this applies to IaaS vendors such as AWS and GCP and SaaS vendors such as Stripe and Auth0. This is also true if API is provided for a fee. In this case, if developers are employed through DevRel, this will lead directly to an increase in revenue, it will be easier to compute the intiative as a cost. In this case, if there is a DevRel team under the marketing department, it will be easier for them to act after a budgetary allocation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of a direct revenue type, DevRel’s values can be looked at with a focus on number of users, number of inquiries, number of API calls, rate of activity, number of cases, and so on. Hands-on activities are effective in increasing the number of users, and to increase the number of cases, policies such as hackathons are easy to initiate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, it is easy for the direct revenue type to conduct DevRel and it is also a form that has many advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;indirect-revenue-type&quot;&gt;Indirect revenue type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a case in which the source of revenue of the main service is elsewhere and API is provided to assist and increase awareness of it. For example, this applies to restaurant service APIs, APIs provided with social significance, and so on. As for use in business, there are many cases in which agreement is obtained by consultation, and there are not many examples that are connected to actual cases. In this case, for DevRel, it is often the case that the purpose is to increase developers’ awareness of it, so it is more advantageous for the DevRel team to be in the development department. It is likely that feedback from developers can smoothly permeate the company and events and so on can also be conducted from the developers’ perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of the indirect revenue type, as revenue is not the aim, there is the problem of not being able to establish goals. Just increasing the number of users does not result in revenue, and on the contrary, this just leads to an increase in the burden on the server, leading to a cost increase. The same applies for the number of API calls. If the main service does not target developers, increasing developers’ awareness of it does not lead to an increase in revenue, making it difficult to implement the policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not good to neglect publicized APIs just because it is not related to revenue. It is likely that the credibility of the main service will be doubted due to unexpected security holes and old and neglected documents. If publicizing an API, it would likely be good to limit it to something that makes dogfooding possible (originally, it should be the other way around, and we should publicize what we use).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibilities for indirect revenue types arise when there is talk of tie-ups between corporations. WIth an API, the development when tying up services can be conducted smoothly. WIthout an API, an API will have to be developed according to the needs of the company with which the tie-up is being conducted for the first time. As a result, it might be an API that cannot be used for tie-ups with other corporations. ALso, if an API is not publicized, it might not be considered for tie-ups in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;branding-type&quot;&gt;Branding type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last is for branding purposes. In this case, publicity of human resources will take the initiative. In the case of branding as well, it would likely be better for the DevRel team to be in the development team. By continuing on-site development, new topics can constantly be provided. Good examples include Cookpad and Class Method (although they probably are not in the forms of DevRel teams). Their aims are likely company branding and an increase in the employment of developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, having engineering blogs, setting up booths at conferences, and so on are carried out as policies. On the contrary, it is likely that user communities are difficult to establish. It is also common for communities to be established with the development language that the company considers itself most skilled in as the theme. It is difficult to quantify branding, but the number of employment entries can be counted quantitatively, so it is a policy that is easy to implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than branding, it is likely that even direct revenue types and indirect revenue types have these goals. Nonetheless, multiple messages will make it difficult to have an effect on the target group, so caution must be exercised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-challenges-of-the-indirect-revenue-type&quot;&gt;The challenges of the indirect revenue type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problems are likely DevRel’s initiative and continuity with regards to indirect revenue types. When there was a large buzz regarding Web2.0 around 2004, many corporations provided APIs, but many of them only distributed information and were unable to generate content. These APIs are still being provided, but they have been all but abandoned. That being said, an increase in users does not necessarily result in revenue, so there is likely no need to intentionally provide support. If architecture undergoes large changes in the future, the API might be closed suddenly. It is a common mistake to think that it is sufficient to just prepare a period of notice, but to developers, this is likely the ultimate inconvenience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Maps API used to be free, but has been made to be paid. It can be said that developers saw this as collateral for continuity and Google was able to switch from a cost to profit department. There is also a free section so in many cases, there is not much influence, but I think that the move to charging a fee is a good one. In particular, Google has a bad habit of immediately closing down its services, so making it paid has made it unable to end at a moment’s notice in the sense of SLA as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if providing functions to developers as an indirect revenue type, there should be consideration as to whether to make it profitable or support it, or to just stop it entirely. Costs on servers are also cheap, so as a result of leaving it there peacefully, discoveries of security holes and the continued publicization of documents that are not maintained might lead to doubt in the main service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevRel is a marketing policy, so it should be initiated after properly deciding on a goal. Without a goal, it is possible that the management ranks will suddenly ask, “Remind me what are you doing this for?” It must be shown that it is an activity that presents proper cost advantages and has value in continuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At MOONGIFT, we provide support for all aspects of DevRel. Please &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;feel free to contact us&lt;/a&gt; regarding the improvement of direct and indirect revenue types, creating systems for branding types, and so on!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>moongift</name></author><summary type="html">If DevRel is looked at as a “marketing method to spread products and services targeting developers,” one might think that it cannot be used if such services are not being made. However, DevRel is something that forms good and continuous relations with developers, so it is an initiative that has a large range and can be used more.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Do DevRel teams belong within marketing or development departments?</title><link href="https://devre.co/devrel/marketing/2019/05/09/developement-marketing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do DevRel teams belong within marketing or development departments?" /><published>2019-05-09T09:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-05-09T09:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://devre.co/devrel/marketing/2019/05/09/developement-marketing</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://devre.co/devrel/marketing/2019/05/09/developement-marketing.html">&lt;p&gt;While DevRel is one sphere of marketing, its nature is of closeness to the developers. There are many actions which would bear no consequence for someone in a different line of work yet are unthinkable for someone working with the developers. I often hear stories of those who, failing to understand this, tread unwittingly on the tiger’s tail, to say, causing great despair for the developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so it is often asked whether DevRel teams belong in marketing or in the development team. In reality, which is the better fit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;devrel-within-marketing&quot;&gt;DevRel within marketing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DevRel is a marketing activity, so the simplest answer would be that, yes, this is where it belongs. This is most likely the reality in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;merits&quot;&gt;Merits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A merit is that the team can work towards goals shared with the marketing team. Their task is to propagate the company’s products and services, and it is important to share in this. They can undertake activities in tune with marketing objectives such as user acquisition and improving activity rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often hear that when an evangelist or advocate has a background in developing, they are called upon for help during the height of development. By being part of the marketing team, they are able to avoid tasks that deviate from their main purpose thanks to the physical distance between them and development. Not doing so would mean that the busyness of development may lead to them being unable to fulfill their evangelist duties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say that marketing does not have the largest budget. Still, the assignment for marketing activities it is most likely larger than what is assigned to the development team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;demerits&quot;&gt;Demerits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the evangelists and advocates with a background as a developer, many of them feel stress when they are away from the development site. A fair few will often return to the development site after a brief intermission for their evangelist activities. Being away from the development site would make it difficult to accumulate practical techniques used on site, even with the latest technological advances. Evangelists and advocates are therefore said to be peddling their skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, there are some who say they struggle to adjust to the marketing atmosphere. Although “technical” in that results manifest as numbers, for a developer, there are many times when the way those numbers are produced is too chancy. When numbers are the objective, the quality can be neglected. It is not rare for someone with a developers perspective to feel stress in such methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;devrel-within-development&quot;&gt;DevRel within development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what if DevRel was in a development team? While the opposite can be said to the marketing case as stated above, there are a few merits and demerits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;merits-1&quot;&gt;Merits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest merit would be being in close proximity to the development site. With easier access to the company technology they would be able to be aware of version upgrades and changes straight away. It would be easy to grasp the development schedule and understand future developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User feedback could be easily communicated to the developing team—a privilege existing only through closeness. A marketing team would have to go through the process of first compiling the information before sharing it with the development team. In addition, as development prioritizes the development team itself, there is the problem that requests from marketing may not always find their destination easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;demerits-1&quot;&gt;Demerits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The greatest demerit would be that the development schedule may wreak havoc on the evangelist’s activities. In a development team, the evangelist is not a specialized role but often has multiple responsibilities as a lead engineer or a CTO, for example. If the development schedule enters a not-so-busy period, there is always the chance it may pick up at anytime. Presentations are scheduled at least a month in advance, so it is not exactly the case they can leap into a presentation whenever their hands are free. While they are in the midst of preparations, they could be hit with fresh waves of development work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, there is the issue of budget. Development teams tend not to allocate much to DevRel. It is usually enough to purchase development tools and products for improving production, but not enough for business trips and other novelties. Therefore, we tend to see a system where planning is undertaken in marketing only for the presentation to be handled by the evangelist. In this case, reconciling development and presentation schedules is often a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-is-the-best-place-to-be&quot;&gt;Where is the best place to be?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The author recommends the following (In order of best to worst).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A department existing in-between development and marketing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The marketing department&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The development department&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we have to pick between marketing and development, I would say it should be marketing. DevRel’s objectives are based more in marketing, and it would be difficult to get results even if it were in the development department. If the development department has a marketing function, it can no longer be said to be a development department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to say the answer is marketing only, would be a misleading statement. I think that, if possible, it would best for DevRel to exist in-between marketing and development, fulfilling an intermediary role, or to belong to the marketing department while having presence in the development department too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evangelists and advocates need to have fluency in both marketing and development. They should bridge with not only external developers but also internal marketing and development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moongift-works-to-develop-communities&quot;&gt;MOONGIFT works to develop communities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MOONGIFT can provide evangelist and advocate services. We can also support your DevRel organization and planning operations. If you are starting DevRel, having problems with an existing system, or want to get better results, &lt;a href=&quot;/contact&quot;&gt;please by all means get in touch with us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>moongift</name></author><summary type="html">While DevRel is one sphere of marketing, its nature is of closeness to the developers. There are many actions which would bear no consequence for someone in a different line of work yet are unthinkable for someone working with the developers. I often hear stories of those who, failing to understand this, tread unwittingly on the tiger’s tail, to say, causing great despair for the developer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The new to existing participant ratio indispensable for community growth</title><link href="https://devre.co/community/2019/05/08/percentage-community.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The new to existing participant ratio indispensable for community growth" /><published>2019-05-08T09:00:00+09:00</published><updated>2019-05-08T09:00:00+09:00</updated><id>https://devre.co/community/2019/05/08/percentage-community</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://devre.co/community/2019/05/08/percentage-community.html">&lt;p&gt;For a community to grow steadily it needs to have a large number of new participants. In offline events, event venue capacity will most determine the number of participants. For example, if 80 people gather in a venue with a capacity of only 50 people, there’s no doubt that there will be a number of people standing and sitting on the floor—not a problem when the environment allows for it, but nobody would ever want to sit on a dirty floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, it is usually capacity which is decided before trying to attract customers. Then, in the community growth process, the ratio of new participants and those who have participated before becomes an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ideal-ratio&quot;&gt;The ideal ratio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ideal ratio of new to existing participants is around 4:6 to 6:4. If this becomes 8 new to 2 existing, then there would be too many new participants. On the other hand, with 8 existing there would be too much of an inner-circle atmosphere which would inhibit community growth. For example, if only 10 new participants came to an event for 50 people, we couldn’t really call this a significant increase. However, there are also problems if there are too many new participants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is the issue with having too many new participants? In the most extreme situation, suppose we have new participants every time; the community is increasing by the number of events x venue capacity. There is a rapidly growing atmosphere in terms of community members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thinking-with-a-funnel&quot;&gt;Thinking with a funnel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s try thinking about this using funnel analysis, a common marketing technique. If 100% of the people were first timers, there would be 0 existing users. Although these people will have all registered, there has been absolutely no repeaters. If people don’t come back again, it doesn’t matter how many new registrations we get. They will quit thinking, “What was different?” “That was boring,” and “It wasn’t useful.” It is hard to call this “establishing a community.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we think with the AARRR model, it corresponds to the ratio from registration to continuation. In a community, if the rate of continuous participation is low, there is no point in increasing only the cumulative number of participants. This becomes the situation when the majority of people feel that the content was different to what they had imagined, or that they’ll participate only when the themes are suited to them. In any case, they can’t be said to be members of a community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The capacity of the event venue and personal circumstances will mean that not everybody can participate every time. Furthermore, there is no need for previous participants to all participate in a row, as we want some degree of new participants. However, the problem is a situation where people leave never to return again. The ideal ratio for this of new to existing is 4:6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-merits-of-46&quot;&gt;The merits of 4:6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are the merits of this ideal participant ratio? The existing participants will contribute to a community atmosphere, and they already know the objectives and vibe. If there are too many new comers, you would need to explain everything from the ground up because they would have no knowledge of the the previous atmosphere. If there is some degree of existing participants, they will kindly guide the first timers, who have have entered into a situation with a new atmosphere and no known faces. It’s surely better for them if there were more people who are used to the atmosphere than those with first-time nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;control-the-ratio&quot;&gt;Control the ratio&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method of controlling the new to existing ratio depends on the number of participants. First, let’s consider situations where the number of participants is just right or a little less than the venue capacity. For example, a case where 45 participants are expected when the capacity is 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, we should promote the event to the existing community in the case our numbers for existing participants are too low. With connpass, we can send messages to community members. This function is used to better publicize the event. If there are not enough new people we need to spread the word beyond our community members. For this we can use websites or social media, for example. It is also a good idea to share information on Facebook where we can expect personal connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, what if an overwhelmingly large number of people register to participate when the venue capacity is much smaller? Say, 150 people wanting to join when the capacity is only 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the recommendation is to use a lottery system rather than going with a first come, first served basis. By doing so, we are able to check the numbers of new and existing participants. We can then control the ratio by using functions (in the case of connpass) to make decisions within the lottery in advance. Various controls are possible such as prioritizing those existing participants who have particularly high participation rates, or new participants who have high participation rates at other events. It’s a good idea to leave a degree of randomness, but caution is required when it comes to the new to existing participant ratio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building a community, we need to be aware of the ratio of new to existing participants every time. If we feel the proportion of new people is too large, there’s the possibility that our content is considered uninteresting. Conversely, if there is a large proportion of existing participants, the result may be that an inner circle atmosphere makes it hard for new people to fit in. Both cases can be considered as warning signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to community growth is a theme that is in tune with the participants. The community will grow if we can maintain a healthy situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;moongift-works-to-develop-communities&quot;&gt;MOONGIFT works to develop communities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MOONGIFT supports developer community growth. As your community managers, we will raise your developer communities. Communities ultimately aim for self-propulsion, and become able to operate independently. If you are looking to build a community or are having problems with an existing one, [please contact us]](/contact).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>moongift</name></author><summary type="html">For a community to grow steadily it needs to have a large number of new participants. In offline events, event venue capacity will most determine the number of participants. For example, if 80 people gather in a venue with a capacity of only 50 people, there’s no doubt that there will be a number of people standing and sitting on the floor—not a problem when the environment allows for it, but nobody would ever want to sit on a dirty floor.</summary></entry></feed>